accelacommunications.com 2006-06-21

# Welcome to Accela Communications - Privacy Policy

Accela Communications, Inc. provides this privacy policy to ensure clear notice and understanding of our information gathering and dissemination practices. We are committed to notify you of the following: 

  1. What personally identifiable information is collected and how the information is used.
  2. With whom collected information may be shared. 
  3. How you can correct or make changes to this information.
  4. What choices are available to you regarding the collection, use, and distribution of collected information. 
  5. What security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under Accela Communications' control.

**What information does Accela Communications collect?**  
Accela Communications collects optional data supplied by visitors through various registration forms, surveys, sweepstakes and contests, as well as information gathered from visitors via our server log. This information allows us to provide a more personalized and robust user experience and allows our vendor customers to better understand and communicate with the audience they are reaching.

**How is registration data used?**  
Accela Communications, Inc. and its customers offer optional information services that require registration. Accela Communications provides some of those services directly while others are provided on behalf of third parties. 

**a.** Information that is collected directly on behalf of Accela Communications may be used to send relevant informa-  
tion about our products and services. Users always have the ability to opt-out of receiving any future mailings. (See the choice/opt-out section below.) This information may also be used to contact users for the administration of prizes and rewards or to respond to customer service requests. 

**b.** Accela Communications, Inc. owns and operates the ITworld.com Site Network. By registering as a member of the ITworld.com Site Network, you will be given unrestricted access to a collection of sponsored content. In return for this content access, your registration data may be shared with the sponsor of that content. Information once transmitted to one of these sponsor companies may also be subject to that company's privacy policy. 

**c.** Accela Communications also acts as a service provider to host registration forms which once completed, allow access to information products and services provided by one or more third parties. Information collected via these registration forms will be transmitted to such third parties and may also, or exclusively be subject to those third party's privacy policies. 

**Passively Collected System Information**  
Accela Communications' webcast application provides a system test that determines whether you can view a webcast from your computer. This test collects information such as platform/operating system, browser type/version, screen resolution, media player information, Internet connection speed and whether Java, JavaScript and cookies are enabled. This information is used to optimize the viewing experience and to troubleshoot webcast viewing problems.

**IP Addresses**   
Our Web server automatically records a visitor's domain and IP address. We use the IP address to identify server problems and administer our Web site, and to analyze click-stream data to better understand user behavior.

**What are cookies and how does Accela Communications use them?**   
Cookies are small files containing information that a Web site uses to track a visit. Both persistent and session cookies are used by Accela Communications. A persistent cookie remains on the user's hard drive for authentication purposes, while a session cookie is temporary and is only used to complete a registration process. (Please refer to your browser's Help function for further information on controlling and setting cookies.) Accela Communications requires session cookies to complete any registration process that we host. 

Accela Communications uses persistent cookies to link visitors to registration information that allows the system to confirm a user's identity and access level to various information products and services. Accela Communica-  
tions also uses this information to track service selections, deliver specific content, and save passwords to eliminate logging in each time a user visits information products and services that we provide directly or on behalf of third party companies or organizations. A password is encrypted within the persistent cookie and cannot be accessed by outside parties. A visitor may choose to reject a persistent cookie and use their login password each time they visit and/or select a service that requires authentication. 

**Log files**   
Accela Communications records Apache Web server logs in the extended log file format. We use server log data to help administer, analyze and measure access to our information products and services. We sometimes link personally identifiable information to log click-stream data to help better understand user's interests and behaviors. 

**Third party ad server**   
We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when users visit our web site. These companies may use information (not including name, address, email address or telephone number) about visitors to the Website in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to such visitors. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.doubleclick.com/us/about_doubleclick/privacy/default.asp).

**Changes to this policy and notification of changes**  
Accela Communications may occasionally update this Privacy Policy. The privacy policy will include the date that changes were last made to this document in a prominent location. Accela Communications encourages you to periodically review this Policy to be informed of how Accela Communications collects and uses collected information. 

**Links**  
Information products and services provided directly by Accela Communications and/or third party companies or organizations may contain links to other Web sites. Accela Communications is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those sites. We encourage our users to be aware of this when they click on any such links and urge them to review the privacy statements of each Web site that collects personally identifiable information. 

**Security**  
Accela Communications maintains security measures intended to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information we collect. Our security systems include authenticated access to internal databases, audits of procedures, and regular reviews of overall Web security. 

**Choice/Opt-Out**  
Users may remove their personal information from Accela Communications' database by sending a request via email to privacy@accelacommunications.com. Also, an 'unsubscribe' link is contained in every promotional email that Accela Communications sends. User's may opt-out of any further such email by clicking on this link. 

**Business Transfers**  
In the event that Accela Communications, or substantially all of its assets are acquired, collected user information may be one of the transferred assets. 

**Correct/Update**  
A user may correct or modify any information previously provided by sending an email to privacy@accelacommunications.com. 

**If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement,  
please contact: **   
Audience Development  
Accela Communications, Inc.  
P.O. Box 9107  
118 Turnpike Road  
Southborough, MA 01772  
Phone: 508-303-9700  
Email: [privacy@accelacommunications.com](mailto:privacy@accelacommunications.com)

|  | 

Other Resources:

**Questions?**

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please contact: 

Audience Development  
Accela Communications, Inc.  
P.O. Box 9107  
118 Turnpike Road  
Southborough, MA 01772  
Phone: 508-303-9700  
Email: [privacy  
@accelacommunications.com](mailto:privacy@accelacommunications.com)
